#### Anjali Sheth

- sheth.anjali@gmail.com
- 502-592-0260
- www.linkedin.com/in/anjali-sheth
- https://github.com/asheth22

## **Areas of Expertise**

Strategy and Planning

Project/Program Management

Customer Experience Management

Healthcare Domain Expert

**Operational Excellence** 

**Data Analytics** 

Business Process Reengineering

**Enterprise Architecture** 

# Education and Certifications

Full Stack Web Development

– Johns Hopkins University

Master of Science in Accounting

Bachelor of Engineering

**PMP Certification** 

Certified Lean Six Sigma Master Black Belt

**Enterprise Architect** 

## **Personal Skills**

Agile Decision-Making

Collaboration and Relationship Building

Innovative and out-of-the-box thinking

Inspire and Build High-Performing Teams

Planning and Execution

Data analysis and problem solving

# Awards and Recognitions:

Operational Excellence Leader of the Year

Best Performer of the Year

#### **Personal Summary**

Global leader with extensive experience in health insurance, manufacturing and service industries. I have a passion to help organizations achieve operational excellence by eliminating waste, improving quality, and effectively leveraging modern technologies to optimize performance. I am a Full Stack Developer, Enterprise Architect, Certified Lean Six Sigma Master Black belt and Certified Project Management Professional. My analytical skills combined with technical expertise and diverse experience, positions me to become a valuable leader in the technology team.

#### **Professional Experience**

### Global Quality and Continuous Improvement Leader Otis Elevators – Current

- Coached business leaders to assess and prioritize business capabilities.
- Partnered with business leaders to develop and implement strategy and roadmap to optimize core functions such as Supply Chain Management, Sales and Marketing and Customer Service
- Collaborated with the digital technology team to optimize the application landscape and align system capabilities with functional business needs.
- Worked with global teams to optimized key business processes and improved efficiency and effectiveness

# Performance Excellence Leader, Product Delivery Centers

Pratt and Whitney: Jan 2018 - Aug 2019

- Responsible for implementation of lean operating system across global product delivery centers to achieve operational excellence and sustain business growth
- Achieved 25% reduction in engine assembly and delivery cost
- Streamlined international shipping and material execution process resulting in reduced aged inventory and lead time
- Developed and executed a strategy and plan to get engine delivery on contract

## **Executive Director, Achieving Business Excellence**

Aetna: Apr 2016 - Dec 2017

- Deployed Lean Operating System across the enterprise
- Achieved \$100M in operational cost savings
- Led multiple strategic programs supporting market growth, new product implementation, customer experience management, and network optimization

# **Director, Business Architecture and Planning**

UnitedHealth Group: 2010 – 2016

- Created highly efficient business architecture team and successfully completed deployment of architecture framework, blue prints, and roadmaps
- Partnered with senior leaders and executives to provide coaching and guidance on roadmap options based on understanding of industry trends and customer expectations.
- Worked with business constituents to ensure process changes and future functional capabilities are supported within strategic roadmaps
- Engaged with Portfolio Management team and Capital Finance partners to define and implement new capital planning process

**Process Improvement Director, Medical Business Solutions** 

Anthem: 2007 - 2009

**Process Consultant, Strategic Solutions** 

Humana: 1999 - 2006